



Hilary Rallo

FRONT-END DEVELOPER AND WEB DESIGNER

CONTACTS

13780 Del Corso Way Apt 217 Broomfield CO 80020

hilaryrallo.com hrallo@icloud.com

Tel 636.368.7373

EDUCATION

B.A. Interactive Media Webster University 2008-2012

KFY SKILLS

Responsive Sites
Wireframing/Mockups
Requirement Gathering
User Experience
Collaboration
QA/Testing
Implementation/Go-Live
Maintenance/Support
Troubleshooting
Agile

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Front-End Web developer with 4 years experience planning and developing client sites. Applicable web development experience includes: communicating and leading internal team to ensure successful development, quality assurance, and delivery of site to client. Strong experience with HTML5, CSS3, grid frameworks, AngularJs, jQuery, and responsive experiences. Experience assuring bug-free and industry standards for best SEO practices. Worked with design team to ensure efficient structure for development infrastructure. Implemented proper use of tools, naming conventions, and other various best practices. Continuously researching best web principles and usability to ensure best user experience. High skills of communication and collaboration as well as ambition to sharpen existing skills and grow lacking skills. Helped to implement agile process and was a scrum master for a development team consisting of 5 people.

EXPERIENCE

Front-end Developer & Scrum Master Integrity | St. Louis, MO | 5/2012 - 8/2013

Integrity is a leader in the St. Louis web marketing scene, helping companies with anything from growing SEO hits to building complex web applications. While there, I was part of a web development team responsible for creating marketing sites, most often through the Wordpress.org CMS. Starting in January I was also responsible for leading a development team as the scrum master using agile.

- Lead team using Agile development process
- Collaborate with design, project managers, and back-end development
- Converted psds into functional websites using wordpress cms with custom built theme and plugins
- Hand-coded HTML5 and CSS3 using bootstrap framework built on dynamic LESS CSS
- Implement and extend various jQuery plugins such as accordions and responsive menus
- Utilized best-practices in HTML5 structures and CSS3 styling to ensure bug-free quality code
- Used Git version control system to ensure code was collaborative and of the highest quality before launch
- Support and maintenance on around 15 different various sites

LESS/SASS HTML5 Javascript PHP Git

TOOLS

Mac OS X
Adobe Suite
Sketch
Codekit
Terminal
MAMP
Chrome
Firefox
Internet Explorer
Safari
FileZilla
xcode
Sublime Text

FRAMEWORKS

Bourbon
Bourbon Neat
Material Design
Angularjs
Bower
Grunt
Gulp
Bootstrap

EXPERIENCE (continued)

Front-end Developer

Rose Design | St. Louis, MO | 8/2013 - 2/2014

Rose Design is a small company helping clients with custom print and web solutions.

- Help teach the current developer newer technologies such as developing responsive and a css preprocessor.
- Help redesign and develop their existing internal site to give them an updated cutting edge look and feel
- · Use svn to track code
- Support and maintenance on several sites

Front-end Developer

Singularity Interactive | Boulder, CO | 2/2014 - Current

Singularity Interactive is a start-up that currently does consulting work with aspirations to be an immersive gaming company. My time is spent helping to build a large-scale custom app, polymer.gloo.us.

- Prototype and build UI for custom app
- Build and upkeep a custom responsive css framework
- Help bridge the gap between development and design teams
- Used Git version control system to ensure code was collaborative and of the highest quality before launch
- Used Angularis to contribute to app and consume APIs